<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-teddy-bear</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85034438/1902-11-16/ed-1/seq-19/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85052116/1903-02-10/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PRESIDENT AND CARTOONIST
          President Roosevclta failure to kill
          a bear on his recent hunting expedi
          tion Into Mluiulppl continue to be a
          matter for almoit dally jest at the
          White Honda Let ho forget brnlnM
          discretion and complete triumph a
          i diminutive major urea has for sometime
          time occupied a prominent place In
          nearly every cartoon published by tbe
          Washington Post It is I a pitiable
          little bear with big innocent eyes
          which are cast furtively at the proil
          dent when he in I the object of the car
          toon and at other time a bear whose
          eyes seem flllod with an unknown
          fearThis
          This miserable cub has afforded the
          president lots of fun and has also bad
          the effect of cooling his ardor for the
          chase At one of the White House
          receptions Mr Berryman the cartoon
          lit was present and as he pawed
          with others in front of tbo president
          and the receiving party Mr Roosevelt
          grasped him by the hand and person
          ally introduced him to Mid Roosevelt
          as the bear man acknowledging at
          tbe same time the amusement which
          the dally appearance of the bear hail
          caused him following It with this
          oonfeulonYou
          You know said ho a feeling of
          pity come over me after I have bad I
          my laugh and I dont believe I could
          find it In my heart ever to kill another
          bearNew York Time
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045366/1906-01-07/ed-1/seq-43/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1906-11-04/ed-1/seq-20/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>DOLLS ABE OUT BEAKS ARE INE
          ATjrif PETS STEAL AWAY THEHEARTS
          HEARTS OF lAU GIRLSMU
          MU Dolly After a HHicn Extmdlnc OverAll
          All Aft and All Countries tiomrthlneof
          of a Back Number Nowlirr fiuecewnil
          nil Rival Only About a Year OldDolla
          Dolls long cherished idolized dolls aretielng
          Doll lng chrbed Idolzl dols
          being supplanted childish heart by I nowtoy
          toy bears Teddy beam they are calledFrom
          From all quarters of the globe comes thodemand
          demand for Teddy bean with poor MisDolly
          Dolly gazing wofully out of her wide openeyos
          eyes powerless t prevent the slipping awayof
          of her power This is achange at once sudden
          den and
          de ad surprisingIt
          I would be wife t nay that no matterwhat
          what sort of toy was first made a doll mustsurely
          surely havebeen the second The reign oftho
          the doll has been extended over ever
          country savage and civilized since anyrecords
          records exist of
          reor toysModern
          Modern dolls have become works of artFew
          Few persons would ever have been inclinedto
          to predict the downfall of Miss Dolly HOfirmly
          firmly has nho bern entrenched in everylittle
          little girls heart
          But even email maidens can be ficklewhen
          when new and lovable Joys come alongThe
          The owners of dolls evidently have noqualms
          qualms whatever in thrusting Miss Dollyaside
          aside to endure lonely fate and i showering
          lag affection on Mr Teddy Bear insteadIt
          I is said that there are 1000 differentkinds
          kinds of dolls manufactured today whilethere
          there are only two kinds of Teddy bean
          large or small the white bear and tho cinnamon
          mon bear Ninetyeight cent I the er
          age price for a doll of good sie Such dollIB
          IB American made with head constructedof
          of sand and glue and I body of cotton e
          celsior or mayhap sawdust Teddy beanare
          are not 0 very cheap toy the smallest ot
          ing IIDut
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1906-11-18/ed-1/seq-14/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE TEDDY BEAR
          CRAZE IN NEW YORK
          OVER in Germany there is a llttl*
          old woman commanding: a com
          pany of more than two thousand
          workers whose busy fingers fly
          from early morning till late at
          night cutting out, stitching: up and put
          ting together plush bears for the Amer
          ican market. The New York people,
          (rownups as well as children, have ap
          parently pone crazy over these bears,
          and they will not be satisfied with any
          but those made by the German frau.
          Years and years ago tUis woman de
          6igned a pattern for a bear which was
          so natural and appealed so to young
          sters that she was culled the mother of
          the bears. Then she had a tiny shop
          in her house and only a few girls to
          help her. That was before the bear
          fad struck America. Now she has a
          factory that covers a whole square and
          the machinery and employes are work
          ed week in and week out at high
          pressure because Young America must
          have his bears. As the orders pile in
          with every mail and tables arrive
          almost hourly the little old frau and
          her workers hold up their two thousand
          pairs of hands in consternation and
          wonder if every man, woman and child
          In America is sending for a whole fam
          ily of bears.
          They are not far wrong. The entire
          country is in the clutches, or rather the
          embrace, of the plush bear. .Even pot
          dogs and dolls have had to step down
          end out. His Majesty Bruin now reign;.
          The bear rage started at the summer
          resorts along the Jersey shore— some
          say it was at Atlantic City. NAt any
          rate, a nice, fat. winsome little brown
          bear sitting on a counter in a board
          walk shop attracted the eyes of a
          youngster, and nothing would do but
          mamma must stop and look at the
          lovely plush animal. Mamma liked, the
          bear, too. He was an excellent pocket
          edition of those big cinnamon bears
          •way up In Bronx Park, and the young
          eter remembered the fun he had had
          one day watching the bears lumber
          around the sides -of the big iron in
          closed pit and give each other love pats
          with their huge paws. He would have
          ft bear pit. too. Only this little plush
          bear looked so clean that it would be
          a shame to get him all dirty and
          frowsy. The youngster took hold of the
          coveted plaything and his delight grew.
          Bruin had such a realistic little hump
          at the back of his netk. and, bully! he
          had a voice and his legs moved.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045366/1906-12-04/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE "TEDDY-BEAR" FAD
          His eyes never wink as they look into
          hers,
          She hugs him, and lugs him, and yet
          he ne'er stirs
          His luck he can't know, for he's lacking
          in sense,
          Yet "Teddy" is cuddled at some man's
          expense.
          His heart is but sawdust, his brain is
          stuffed hair,
          But all t}ie girls worship the dear
          "Teddy-Bear."
          The "Teddy-Bear" fad has struck
          Minneapolis!
          It has not as vet reached the ridicu
          lous extremes attained in the east, vet
          it is progressing in a very healthy
          maniier.
          Tne Teddy-Bear, as a child's play
          thing, arrived some time ago. For sev
          eral months he has been increasing in
          numbers and bringing proportionately
          greater joy to baby hearts, and more
          numerous smiles to chubby, infant
          faces
          But the Teddy Bear as a fad, is a new
          arrival. The fad seems to be spread
          ing to beat mumps in a country school
          The susceptible ones are voung women
          of the "in society" class
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93055779/1907-01-10/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>FAD OF IK
          TEDDY BEAR
          CAIRO MERCHANTS COULD
          REAPED A HARVEST
          CHRISTMAS TIME.
          HAVE
          AT
          Main began failing early yesterday
          morning and lurried to snow afier (lav
          light and snow felt most of the day.
          According lo the measurement at the
          weather bureau the rain fall was ."8
          of an Inch and the snow fall 3.3 I
          inches.
          The maximum temperature was ?i
          and the minimum 2$, the later pre
          vailing ai 7 m At 12 o'clock las
          night the street record was 27.
          Ye.terday's government bulletin re
          ported rain from 20 points, the heav
          iest being 1.24 inches at Parkersbur
          101 at Evansville. S2 at Louisville
          Helow zero temperatures were report
          ed as follows: BIsmark 22. Dulutb 12
          IF THEY'D HAD EM
          The Origin of the Craze What Was
          An Amusing Toy For Children
          Has Been Adopted By Fool
          ish Women As a Fad.
          ON 10E
          RIVERS
          Cache River Sending Out Record
          Breaking Flood General Condi
          tions Not Alarming,
          Cache creek i.s Ik
          never before known
          Creek and Dig creek,
          has fallen inland hi
          overflowing and ove
          Cairo Opera House
          O. I (WILLIAMSON Man
          One Night only -t y
          Saturday Jan. I
          First time here. Direct from
          Powera' Theatre, Chicago, where
          it was the hit of the eaon.
          The Maurice Campbell Co. vine
          Presents
          Henrietta Crosman
          in Ernest Denny's Great Modern
          Comedy Success
          ALL OF -A Sl'DDl'N
          f e; o o v
          Prices - Entire lower Moor $1 Mj
          first two row Dross Circle 41,
          next two rows 75c, halanee 50c.
          Gallery 2oe, Seats on sale Friday
          14
          One solid wek, starling
          Monday Jan.
          Matins Sat ur lay.
          The famous Jewel kclley
          Stock - o.,
          Presenting the Young Southern
          Romantic Actor Mr Jewell Kel
          ler and a big company of 18.
          All special seenerv. fi big Spec
          ialties. All New Plays.
          MONDAY NIGHT
          The Land of The Midnight
          Sun.
          Ldis free Mond'v night un
          der the usual enndi i in.
          PP.ICES - LOO, We, and
          Seats on sale Mondav.
          One night only
          Monday Jan
          Second Trium-disl Tour of
          8ensation of the Cent try
          21
          the
          George H.Brennan
          Preients
          THE CLANSMAN
          By THOMAS DIXON, Jr.,
          From His Two Famu Novel,
          "The Leopard's Spot" and "Tie
          Clansman"
          Direct from Record-Break 'ng
          Engagement in New York ity
          and Chicago.
          Metropolitan Caet of Forty
          Principal!, Small army ofSuper
          nuroerariea and Troop of Horaee
          Splendid New Scenic Produc
          tion. WARNING. Order your seat
          by mail, lending remittance
          with order. In thle way you
          will avoid having to pay exces
          sive prices to speculators, aa
          was the case last reason with
          this attraction.
          PRICES- Entire lower floor
          1 SO, First 4 rows Drew Circle
          SI , Balance Dres Circle TV .
          Gallery soc.
          Seats on Sale Saturday
          Cairo merchants were besieged at
          Christmas time with requests for
          Teddy Bears. Bverybody wanted to
          give ttie small Doy and girl in ins
          family one of these cn'est of all toys.
          The fail of carrying "Teddy Bears '
          has become almost national. It Is
          not confined to the children hut the
          "499" of New York and the fa-hi"n
          able women of other cities cultivate
          tne fad
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1907-01-24/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ICnowii to o Yni Tnhllc PuIItcM PuIItcMNo n &lt; jMfin jMfinNo fro froNo &lt;&gt; No
          other
          cartoonist ca I Is known personally personallyby by 1 so many poMIc Ic men and M his kmg
          resi residence residence reeldeuce ¬ dence here ha has given Yen him hi a grasp of o af
          affairs atfain affairs ¬ fairs that can be bad nowhere else cia He Heexcels Heexceb
          Heexcels excels in his freehand likenesses of ofstatesmen oratatesmell ofstatesmen
          statesmen ami nd hi Ida humor uniformly Ionnly te of oftbe oCthe ofthe the sort that
          leaves Jeav no sting His local localacquaintance 10caJaequaJntance localacquaintance
          acquaintance is large targeTbe largeThe e eTbe Tbe Roosevelt bear berca r waa V a Berryman
          Berrymancreation BeI17ncftalJon BerymanrsatIon creation He used the theJttttJe iiHOe iIItU
          animal for forthe forthe forthe the first It time during Ute President bear bearhunt
          beilrhunt barhunt hunt in Mississippi MiasIasi four or flv five years ago agoand apand
          ageand and continued thereafter to identify the tbebear the1tea thebear bear 1tea with Mr
          Roosevelt and the White WhiteHouse WbfteHbUM WhiteHouse House Other artists took up the
          Roose Roosevelt Rooe8It Roosevolt ¬ volt 8It bear in course of time and popular
          popularized POPUIarned popularPzed ¬ ned it the tM country over It became be alM a acraze
          aentz aersz craze entz which ultimately spread abroad What hnt the he President Said
          SaidMeeting SRIIMeeting SaidMeeting Meeting the cartoonist recently recentl at a so social
          Metal soelal cial function the President said Id t &lt; b him himMr himMr himMr
          Mr Berryman that little bear of e your yourhas YO YOha yours yourshas
          has ha put the doll baby out of business BuIll BuIllAoo businesoMid businessAnd
          And so it has and nd Berryman te is not in infrequently Infrequently Infrequently
          frequently designated deslgnat d the bear nu nuMiniature man manMiniature manMiniature
          Miniature bears bMrseomieal comical little felk felkHave fell fellh fellowo fellowohave
          Have h ye bad a tremendous sale le This Thismeant has hasmeant linemeant
          meant a fortune for the manufacture manufactureand manuhaeturend manufacturersand
          and dealers dettersU all due to the newspaper newspapcrefetkm newspapercrdllUon
          newspapercrtidtlon
          crefetkm from Berrymans pencil Be Bebooks Bear Berbooks Bearbooks
          books have also been the fad The eAr cartooniat eArtoonlM eartoonlst
          tooniat however has had no share in the thicommercial theeommerelAI thecommercial
          commercial evolution of the animal and andthus andthll6 andtitus
          thus escaping the octopus continues eenU t tdelight to todfJlght todelight &lt;
          delight the multitude by b drawing pi piture pic pictu plc plctures
          ture tu turesMr
          tureMr
          Mr Berryman was recently t17 elected t tmembership to tomfmbershlp tomembership
          membership In the Gridiron Club and andto Is Isto Isto
          to be initiated at the Annual annual dinner to 1 1held be bebeld beheld
          held at the New Willard next Satarda Satardanight sturdanight Saturday Saturdaynight
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-08-04/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>DRAMATIZE
          TEDDY BEARS
          NEW EXTRAVAGANZA WILL HAVE
          NOVEL FEATURES
          FADDY LITTLE TOY TO PROVIDE
          PLOT
          Production Will Follow Lines Made
          Popularly "The Wizard of
          Oz," and "Babes In
          Toyland"
          The Teddy bear is to be drnmatlied.
          Harry Askln, manager of Ezra Kendall,
          who Is now at the. Mason, is the man
          who first sny the dramatic possibilities
          of the little faddy toys, and astute ob
          servers of things theatrical say that Mr.
          Askln probably has hit upon a gold
          mine. Of course some gold mines don't
          pay dividends, bu"t this one Askln is
          confident will nqt prove that kind of a
          mine. ¦
          His Idea is to turn the Teddy bears
          Into a big extravaganza, which shall fol
          low along the path blazed by "The Wiz
          ard of Oz" and "Babes in Toyland."
          &lt;ffhere will he brilliant ballets, surpris
          ing stage effects and the usual extrava
          ganaa riot of color and light.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93055779/1907-12-15/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>: Collar For "Fritz.'
          Dear Santa Cdaus: Please bring mo
          a teddy bear, and a dolly that goes to
          Bleep and some ribbon for my bair and
          some candy and nuts and Santa Claus
          please bring my dog, Frit; a nice col
          lar with hla name on it. That's all.
          your little girl,
          , MARY STUART WARP,
          721 Thirty-eighth street, Cairo, HI.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1955-09-15/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ELECTRONICS MAKE TEDDY BEAR
          MORE CUDDLY AND RELAXING
          LONDON UP). —Three British electronics engineers* re
          ported today the invention of a new-style Teddy bear de
          signed to put people to sleep.
          All an insomnia sufferer has to do is plug the bear Into
          an electric socket and then cuddle up with it. they said.
          Explained Norman Parker, one of the inventors:
          “Air is then pumped by an artificial lung in and out of
          the Teddy bear at the rate of 10 to 12 breaths a minute,
          the normal breathing rate of an adult when asleep.
          “This slow, rhythmic breathing by the Teddy bear aids
          the brain to slow down the user’s breathing rate and also
          helps the body to relax.”
          For adults who might feel silly cuddled qp with a Teddy
          hear, the invention also comes in the form of a pulsing
          pillow.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1950-04-30/ed-1/?sp=107</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016689/1911-05-24/ed-2/?sp=13</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88068010/1907-12-20/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85059715/1907-12-24/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>LACO LINWOOD YOUNG.
          Dear Santa Claus:
          I want a Teddy bear, a doll baby
          and set of dishes, and a table and
          little rocking chair and lots of candy
          and nxits.
          Your friend.
          NELLIE MULLIGAN.
          Water street
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-roller-coasters</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1884-07-27/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>An Unique Amusement, St. Paul has added another popular attrac tion to her amusements
          which will unques tionably meet with large public attention anil approval. We refer to thu
          roller coaster re cently erected at tho corner of Thirteenth and Cellar streets, by the
          Ramsey County Gravity Hailroad company. On approaching tbe spot in the evening the
          atteution is attracted by the brilliancy of three powerful electric lamps which shed a
          strong pleasant UghtOß one of the gayest scenes imaginable. An amphitheater of large
          extent, gayly painted in striking colors, the many hucd dressei of feminine toilets, and
          the ringing hearty laugh attest jovialty, good humor and furious fun. The apparatus, a
          narrow track acted in midair, which descends in curves and sharp inclines to the further
          side. T.vo trains of two coaches each are run over tiie track every minute, an j the
          momentum Obtained is sufficient to carry the cars and nsrers up the incline on the home
          stretch back to the starting point. Such briefly tlu Bu_h_ feature of the coaster, but in
          describing the ride we shall have to pause a monte ut to catch breath and i ooi thoughts
          in order to do the en- Inineiuir. ixhiler_.ti.i_. sport justice. The cir- MX) feet. ttM
          speed tremendous, just li cc the flight of a bird t-irou_.li the air. and when you teach
          tbe goal yoa tad that yoa bave had a new and exciting experience in Tlie whole amusement
          consists in the great speed, and yet it is as safe and harmless a&lt; inging in a crib. It
          is undoubtedly a
          some, healthy, fascinating ttttng. the
          whole establishment is conducted quietly
          and everything possible has been done for
          the comfort and pleasure of patrons. The
          c in the city frequent the place,
          and w* would strongly advise both ladies and
          I nun. if they wish the unique, que- r
          tion of firing through the air. to try the
          The charges are two rides, 1,000 feet,
          for Live cents.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-05-25/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>SCENIC RAILWAY PRODUCES MANY SURPRISES AND THRILLS.
          j. """""'''"aaaMi 1 1. laasssaaaini ,1, J.IMJHaamaaOTTSraSBWaSawlan
          THE SCENIC n.ULWAY OXE
          The Scenic Railway on the IMka was
          one of the first amusement concessions
          to open Its doors to the public, and a ride
          on the switcbba'fc railway Is said to pro
          duce thrills that delight the venturesome.
          and frighten he timid.
          The tracks are so arranged that the two
          terminals are close together In the r
          villon. doubling the action at the start
          and at the finish. After the train haa luft
          the station the ride is saM to be thri'ling
          and full of sensations and surprises,
          caused bj- the varrlsj' speed, the rise and
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1906-06-17/ed-1/?sp=58</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The park Is large, having an area of seventy
          eight acres, and has room in it for much be
          .le9 the Wild West Sho There is, for in
          stance, the big pavilion, here vocal and in
          THE CARROUSEL, THE CHILDREN'S DELIGHT.
          CORRIGANS ICE CRE.VyI BOOTH.
          VHERE ONC CAN TAKE A -TOUR" AROUN J
          THE WORLD AT A SMALL PRICE.
          strumental concerts are given. Then there Js
          the roller coaster, which is said to one of the
          largest? in the country, and which is equipped
          with special safety devices.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076843/1908-08-14/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Perhaps tho scenic railway is known
          more generally to those who would
          lino their Interiors with momentary
          thrills. This rido consists of a series
          of cars strung together. There are
          brakes between each car and tho
          levers are manned by strong-armed
          boys from the railway yards. To them
          there aro no thrills. It's monotonous
          ns driving the cows home from pasture
          for them. Even catching a pair spoon
          ing while the train is running through
          the blackness of a mimic Canadian
          forest, can't mako them feel weary. It
          happens on every trip.
          Tho average scenic railway runs up
          a 45-degreo incline or rather Is hauled
          up by a chain and you are ready for
          tho first dip. The brakemen release
          their lovers and down tho cars go
          faster than tho New York-Chicago 1S
          hour limited.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045555/1910-07-30/ed-1/?sp=25</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Making Thrills for Coney
          I
          tlunfi Left to Chance in the Domain of Roller
          Coasters for the Dollars Cease to Trickle in
          After Every Island Accident New Devices
          Used Year by Year
          dollars are In
          million
          uTLVB
          mechanical rides and
          eted in m
          nt
          T alter railways In this country
          A RnJ several million people con
          nickels nnd dimes each
          their
          tri utt and
          to make the proprietors
          JnJIOCr richer The recent wreck ut
          Ownlen hland wherein a car III IIWltt
          Si IIenl oft the truck nnd caused
          Icnl to seven persons lias
          injuries
          1Vre tuntlon to the real dangers of
          nfhrnrS Aa a veteran exhlbl
          tron t t6 the beach Uowery remarked iMt
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-09-11/ed-1/?sp=19</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Hence the roller coaster. It stands in Scot land, in Coney Island, in Brazil, in
          Yucatan. It is numbered in tens of thousands, and mill ions ride In it every year. It has
          made its in ventors millionaires. Yet they took only tha essence, the spiritual part, of
          the cellar door, freed it from its homely surroundings, exalted it. elaborated it,
          capitalized it and made it a. mint to coin the cellar door impulse into good currency. The
          mint works on a grand scale. The first roller coaster was 4.» feet Ion:;, an{ the highest
          drop on the line was one of ten feet. The thrill was somewhat more intense than that to be
          gained from a parlor rocking chair; it was rather more like the sensation of working 4
          wooden lawn swing. To-day there is a rolle? coaster at Brighton Beach where the track is
          11G feet high at one point, and there is a drop of eighty-five feet. "When the car plunges
          down that descent the passenger literally leaves his scat for an instant, and a3 he sees
          Coney Is!a:r4 leaping up to meet him he knows how a base* ball feels when a .400 batsman
          swings on if t with the bases full. That first roller coaster cost $1,500. The bisj 3cenic
          railways at Toney Island to-day coa| about $00,000 each. The smaller ones, such a3 are
          shipped cut to Rio de Janeiro or Yokohama, represent an Investment of S-K&gt;,&lt;"&gt;oo
          each before
          they have carried a passenger. It is estimated that 550,090,000 is invested in sliding-
          amuse ments of one sort or another in the United States alone. More than half the
          population o? the country lives within an hour's ride of ons or ancther of them, for they
          are in a thcusan 1 of our clues. If the cellar door impulse is not turned into hard
          dollars it is certainly not for lack of the machinery to do it or of willingness to
          furnish the machinery. A single firm, tha same which operated the first ••switchback' in
          1884, now has $8,000,000 Invested in the busi ness. Its profits are enormous.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87078082/1911-09-06/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1914-08-08/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>BIG ROLLER COASTER BUILT
          Thrilling Dips and Dives at Great Min
          nesota State Fair.
          Did you ever take a ride on a big
          roller coaster about half a mile long
          and find yourself fairly gasping for
          breath, though thrilled by pleasure, as
          you maBe the deep dips and sharp
          turns? If you have experienced the
          sensation you know why some persons
          are so crazy about it that they refuse
          to get off until they have taken a dozen
          rides or more. ,%l~-
          A gigantic roller coaster has been
          erected at the Minnesota State Fair.
          Grounds this summer that is said to
          be one of the largest ever built in the
          Middle West. It will please thousands
          at the Fair, Sept. 7-12. A cable car-
          The Good Roads Exhibit at the- Min-
          nesota State- Fair, Sept. 7-19, is de
          signed to compare good and bfd meth
          mt*m jmt mnmA huildina. floW?"
          Every farmer who has some
          thing to sell or who wants to buy
          something is invited to send his de
          sires direct to the Pioneer office or.
          FOrf SALE
          One 3 year old mare.-Fred Peter
          son, Splway* ,Minn.
          A steeple chase, in which horses will 1 Some of the greatest jumpers in
          hurdle barriers placpd all around the America will compete in this chase,
          big race track, will be a feature at the When horses stumble, riders often
          Minnesota State Fair, Sept 7 to 12. take dangerous tumbles.
          ries the two-seated car to the top, been arranged for the young folks
          which is so high that a view of all the
          grounds is afforded. Then the car is
          suddenly released, and^a long deep dip
          is taken that leaves a great empty
          space in your stomach. You shoot up
          a hill, take a sharp turn, another dip,
          a dozen more ascents, dips, and dives,
          and back you are again -ready for an
          other ride.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1915-08-29/ed-1/?sp=24</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ROLLER COASTER AT KRUQ
          PARK FURNISHES THRILLS
          One of tha most popular of tha many
          forma of rleasure to be found at Krug
          park la m riding tha giant coaster. The
          coaster, conceded to be the moat pleas
          ureful of all rides, gains Its popularity
          through the fact that it furnishes threo
          distinct thrills In the ride which requires
          sixty-two seconds to cover a distance
          of three-fourths of a mile. The ride la
          of sn exciting nature and is greatly ex
          hilarating. The coaster Is closely con
          tested for the popularity honors by the
          frolic, which Is also a thrilling ride. It
          Is a combination of a carrousel and a
          circle swing and In riding the frolto
          one encounters a new form f locomo
          tion, the big basketa traveling in a cir
          cle swinging Inwardly and outwardly at
          the same time. The annual tmsket pic
          nic, w tilth la an occasion for much com
          ment and an Item of Interest to hundreds
          of families, haa been arranged to take
          place Labor day. The management haa
          made adequate arrangements co accom
          modate all with table and .'halra that
          annually attend this feast of pleasure.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020662/1955-07-13/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016244/1955-04-20/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Says
          NEW YORK i^-So far the Rus
          sians haven’t claimed they invent-,
          ed the roller coaster.
          If they ever do, they’re going to
          have to fight Joe McKee, who at
          67 is the acknowledged dean of the
          roller coaster industry.
          “The first roller coaster in his
          tory was built in Pittsburgh in
          1904,” Joe recalled. “And 1 got
          started in the business as a car
          penter the following year.”
          In 51 years some 600 roller
          coasters have been built through
          out the world. Joe figures he has
          had a hand in designing or build-j
          ing about 300 himself—more than
          any other man.
          “Only 18 men—all carpenters—
          have ever had anything to do with
          designing roller coasters.” Joe
          said, “and there are only four
          now left alive. I'm the oldest.
          “The roller coaster grew out of
          the old scenic railway. We had
          nothing to go by, so we operated
          by rule of thumb.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1941-03-30/ed-1/?sp=90</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84031081/1922-06-23/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-telephone-invention</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014896/1876-11-18/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Audible Speech Conveyed Two
          MUch by Telcjrrriili.
          The Boston Advertiser prints an in
          teresting account ot an experiment m
          carrying on a conversation by word of
          mouth over telegraph wire, made by
          Alexander Graham Bell and Thomas
          Watson. Telephones were placed at
          either end of a telegraph line owned
          by th "Walworth Manufacturing Com
          nanv. extendiuir from their office in
          Boston to their factory in Cambridge
          port, a distance of about two miles.
          The comnativ's battery, consisting of
          nine Daniels cells, was removed from
          tlie circuit and another ot ten carbon
          elements substituted. Articulate con
          versation then took placo through the
          wire. The sounds, at first taint and
          indistinct, b came suddenly loud and
          intelligible. Mr. Bell in Boston and
          Mr. "Watson in Cambridge took notes
          of what was said and heard, and the
          comparison of the two records shows
          that the transmission was almost per-
          fectlv accurate. Conversation was car
          ried on for about half an hour, gener-
          ally in an ordinary tone of voice, but
          often in whispers. Miie creuit oi tins
          important discovery is due to Mr. Bell
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032573/1877-04-19/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A Wonderful Invention.
          Thrco vears ago the Herald predict
          ed that 'the time would come when
          the human voice aud musical sound
          could be carried long distances over
          electric wires, that the prima douna
          who sang in New York could be heard
          in the music halls of San Francisco.
          The Boston Olobeoi Tuesday, has a
          dispatch three-quarters of a column
          long, which was spoken in Salem and
          heard and printed in Boston. Prof.
          G. A. Bell, the inventor of the won
          derful system, gave a lecture about
          the telephone "m Salem, and to illus
          trate the working capacity, he had the
          operator in Boston give the audience
          the news from Washington. Every
          word was heard all over the hall, and
          the spectators wore so astonished that
          thev broke into applause, and, what is
          marvellous, the applause was heard
          in the Boston office, eighteen miles
          away. The Globe says: "Coughing
          and singing were then heard, and a
          varictv of questions were then asked
          from the Salem end, and the news
          came fleeting along that the engineers
          of the Boston aud Maine railroad had
          struck. General Cogswell asked if
          trains were running; the answer was
          clear and distinct that they were not
          at half past five o'clock. Pro. Bell in
          troduced the Rev. E. C. BoIle, who
          said, 'I shake hands with you cordial
          ly in imagination, twenty miles away.'
          The Rev. E. S. Atwood akcd, 'Doe
          it rain 'It docs not in Boston,' was
          Mr. Watson's answer. Pro. Gage, tho
          electrician, then spoko through the
          telephone, endeavoring to have his
          voice recognized. This could not bo
          done, as Mr. Watson was not familiar
          with tho voice. Mr. Shaje Zsawa was
          recognized, Mr. Wattou being perfect
          ly familiar with his tones. One of the
          assistant in Boston then said that
          'Hold tho Forf would bo sung in Bos
          ton, and the tunc which followed was
          readilv recognized. Prof. Bell closed
          his lecture bv briefly staling the prac
          tical uses to whit-h ho was confident
          the telephone could be applied.
          Hearty applause was afforded the lec
          turer as he finished, and people flocked
          about the stage in large numbers to
          more closely examine the wonderful
          instrument that had placed them iu
          audible communication with people
          nearly twenty -miles away. The lec
          ture and experiment were an unquali
          fied success." New York Herald.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1877-03-31/ed-1/?sp=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Ro, on a sultry Sunday morning, hotter according
          to the thermometer than any day before it last year,
          a small group of gentlemen entered the Main Build-
          ing and stationed themselves in the gallery at the
          east end. The party divided, and half went to each
          end of the gallery. The great organ was between,
          and neither half of the party could hear or sce the
          other. Then Prof. A. Graham Bell brought out his
          telephone. Wires for telegraphing were laid along
          ihe gallery; a battery was set at work, anda contin.
          uous current was sent along the line. The stations
          n this line were only two; one at each end of the
          gallery. At each station there was a little, ordinary
          electro-magnet, such as people see usually on the
          ~able in a small telegraph office, and are in general
          familiar with. Beside the magnet there wae nothing
          except a fow funnels, These were of different shapes,
          but they agreed in each having one end eovered
          with stretehed parchiment, like a drum-head. On
          4he center of each of these drum-heads, oatside, a
          small plate of metal, G. was cemented fast. The
          Jdiagram hows a more elaborate form of the funnel,
          one that is provided with a movable ring or hoop
          (below the letter A) which can be adjusted by set-
          screws, H, H. By these means the parchment, F, IY,
          over the end of the funnel, can be made tighter or
          jooser. ln the earlier stages of the invention the
          sonnd. The instructions for nse were very simple.
          The sender of a message was to talk into ene funnel
          the receiver was to apply the other funnel to his ear,
          Fach was to hold his funnel so that the parchment
          wonld be opposite the poles of the electro-maunet,
          and very close to them; just so that the little picee
          of metal, G, mounted on the parchment, should not
          yuite touch the poles.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82000205/1888-03-19/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1899-07-09/ed-1/?sp=26</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>America Is the birthplace of the telephone.
          ItH discovery was tnndo generally known
          In Philadelphia during June 187G 100 years
          after the sinning of the Declaration of In
          dependence and at the Centennial exposi
          tion which commemorated thnt event. The
          History of the Invention of the telephone Is
          In many respects tlio mo t marvelous and
          Interesting part of thin one of the world's
          wonders.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1906-04-22/ed-1/?sp=41</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>America Is the birthplace of the telephone.
          ItH discovery was tnndo generally known
          In Philadelphia during June 187G 100 years
          after the sinning of the Declaration of In
          dependence and at the Centennial exposi
          tion which commemorated thnt event. The
          Htory of the Invention of the telephone Is
          In many respects tlio mo t marvelous and
          Interesting part of thin one of the world's
          wonders.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1915-02-04/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A WONDER OF THE AGES.
          Man Standing on Atlantic
          Coast Can Hear Conversa
          tion on Pacific Side.
          Less than forty years ago Alexan
          der Graham Bell, standing in a little
          attic at 6 Exeter Place", Boston, sent
          through a crude telephone, his own
          invention, the first spoken words ev
          er carried over a wire and the words
          were heard and understood by his
          associate, Thomas A. Watson, who
          was at tho receiver in an adjacent
          room. On that day, March 10, 1876,
          the telephone was born, and the
          first message went over the only
          telephone line in the world a line
          less than a hundred feet long. The
          world moves a long way ahead in
          the span of one man's life. On Mon
          day afternoon, January 25, this
          same Alexander Graham Bell, sitting
          in the offices of the American Tele
          phone Telegraph company at New
          York, talked to this same Thomas A.
          Watson in San Francisco, over-a wire
          stretching 3,400 miles across the con
          tinent and part of a system that in
          cludes 9,000,000 telephones, connect
          ed by 21,000,000 miles of wires.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1922-08-03/ed-1/?sp=9</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075284/1915-01-28/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>In a little workshop in Boston, June
          2, 1875, it was Alexander Graham Bell
          who spoke and Thomas A. Watson
          who heard the first message ever sent
          by telephone. “Come here Watson, I
          want you,” were the first words ever
          conveyed over a wire. That wire was
          only sixty feet in length. The line
          used Monday is 3,400 miles long.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075258/1948-05-05/ed-1/?sp=10</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85025407/1934-09-21/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1903-11-27/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>